

Martin Šimák

Electrical engineering student

- ▶ 10 February 1999, Czechia
- ▶ ISTQB Certified Tester
- European driving license class B

Skills

TeX	advanced
Linux (Arch/Debian) advanced	
AWR MO	advanced
Matlab	advanced
CST Studio Suite	intermediate
Python	intermediate
С	intermediate
C++	beginner
Czech	native
English	C1/C2
German	A1

Profile

I am an electrical engineering student with a major focus on radio-frequency engineering. Currently, I also work on a microwave research project for the faculty and as a test engineer for a prominent telecommunication company. Apart from my career interests, I have played the piano for 12 years, hence I have a strong passion for music, and I enjoy most kinds of sports.

Education

Electronics and Communications

2022 - present

FEE CTU in Prague

I have chosen this master's degree programme with a specialization in Radio Communications and Systems where I further deepen my knowledge in radio-frequency engineering, such as radar systems and wireless communications.

Open Electronic Systems

2018 - 2022

FEE CTU in Prague

For my bachelor's degree studies, I had chosen this programme focused on the fundamentals of electrical engineering from the theoretical viewpoint which offered me a robust understanding of the principles required for further research.

Maturity exam

2014 - 2018

Pierre de Coubertin Grammar School in Tábor

Employment history

Research assistant

2023-present

FEE CTU in Prague

Thanks to my good results during the course of microwave circuit design, I have been offered participation in a microwave research project for a Czech company Argotech. This involves further improving my understanding of microwave circuits, performing 3D EM analyses, calibrating measurement devices etc.

Junior Test Engineer

2022-present

2N TELEKOMUNIKACE a.s.

Working in a modern, international telecommunication company helped me get a better understanding of software development and engineering practices. Nowadays, I specialize in Python scripting for automated software testing.

Mathematics and physics lecturer

2021

FEE CTU in Prague

During the summer semester of the academic year 2020/2021, I co-lead the courses in high-school mathematics and physics for students of the faculty.

Junior Helpdesk Operator

2021, 2020

S&T CZ s.r.o.

This summer job involved working for an extern company delivering technical support for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Czech Republic.

Contact

- +420 602 574 563
- martin.simaak@gmail.com
- github.com/simakma5

Tour guide

Castle Orlík, Castle Konopiště

2018, 2019

During this summer job, I have conducted large groups of people in both Czech and English, which helped me improve my public presentation in both languages.

Fitter

2015, 2016, 2017

EFAFLEX-CZ s.r.o.

From my first regular summer job, I gained the practical experience of a manual labourer in a mechanical company.